<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<lfm status="ok"><artist><name>Alessandra Amoroso</name>
<mbid>cf20d23c-ba1d-4311-9be0-e65320b5a6b5</mbid>
<url>https://www.last.fm/music/Alessandra+Amoroso</url>
<image size="small">https://lastfm.freetls.fastly.net/i/u/34s/2a96cbd8b46e442fc41c2b86b821562f.png</image>
<image size="medium">https://lastfm.freetls.fastly.net/i/u/64s/2a96cbd8b46e442fc41c2b86b821562f.png</image>
<image size="large">https://lastfm.freetls.fastly.net/i/u/174s/2a96cbd8b46e442fc41c2b86b821562f.png</image>
<image size="extralarge">https://lastfm.freetls.fastly.net/i/u/300x300/2a96cbd8b46e442fc41c2b86b821562f.png</image>
<image size="mega">https://lastfm.freetls.fastly.net/i/u/300x300/2a96cbd8b46e442fc41c2b86b821562f.png</image>
<image size="">https://lastfm.freetls.fastly.net/i/u/300x300/2a96cbd8b46e442fc41c2b86b821562f.png</image>
<streamable>0</streamable>
<ontour>0</ontour>
<stats><listeners>43770</listeners>
<playcount>855622</playcount>
</stats>
<similar><artist><name>Emma</name>
<url>https://www.last.fm/music/Emma</url>
<image size="small">https://lastfm.freetls.fastly.net/i/u/34s/2a96cbd8b46e442fc41c2b86b821562f.png</image>
<image size="medium">https://lastfm.freetls.fastly.net/i/u/64s/2a96cbd8b46e442fc41c2b86b821562f.png</image>
<image size="large">https://lastfm.freetls.fastly.net/i/u/174s/2a96cbd8b46e442fc41c2b86b821562f.png</image>
<image size="extralarge">https://lastfm.freetls.fastly.net/i/u/300x300/2a96cbd8b46e442fc41c2b86b821562f.png</image>
<image size="mega">https://lastfm.freetls.fastly.net/i/u/300x300/2a96cbd8b46e442fc41c2b86b821562f.png</image>
<image size="">https://lastfm.freetls.fastly.net/i/u/300x300/2a96cbd8b46e442fc41c2b86b821562f.png</image>
</artist>
<artist><name>Giorgia</name>
<url>https://www.last.fm/music/Giorgia</url>
<image size="small">https://lastfm.freetls.fastly.net/i/u/34s/2a96cbd8b46e442fc41c2b86b821562f.png</image>
<image size="medium">https://lastfm.freetls.fastly.net/i/u/64s/2a96cbd8b46e442fc41c2b86b821562f.png</image>
<image size="large">https://lastfm.freetls.fastly.net/i/u/174s/2a96cbd8b46e442fc41c2b86b821562f.png</image>
<image size="extralarge">https://lastfm.freetls.fastly.net/i/u/300x300/2a96cbd8b46e442fc41c2b86b821562f.png</image>
<image size="mega">https://lastfm.freetls.fastly.net/i/u/300x300/2a96cbd8b46e442fc41c2b86b821562f.png</image>
<image size="">https://lastfm.freetls.fastly.net/i/u/300x300/2a96cbd8b46e442fc41c2b86b821562f.png</image>
</artist>
<artist><name>Noemi</name>
<url>https://www.last.fm/music/Noemi</url>
<image size="small">https://lastfm.freetls.fastly.net/i/u/34s/2a96cbd8b46e442fc41c2b86b821562f.png</image>
<image size="medium">https://lastfm.freetls.fastly.net/i/u/64s/2a96cbd8b46e442fc41c2b86b821562f.png</image>
<image size="large">https://lastfm.freetls.fastly.net/i/u/174s/2a96cbd8b46e442fc41c2b86b821562f.png</image>
<image size="extralarge">https://lastfm.freetls.fastly.net/i/u/300x300/2a96cbd8b46e442fc41c2b86b821562f.png</image>
<image size="mega">https://lastfm.freetls.fastly.net/i/u/300x300/2a96cbd8b46e442fc41c2b86b821562f.png</image>
<image size="">https://lastfm.freetls.fastly.net/i/u/300x300/2a96cbd8b46e442fc41c2b86b821562f.png</image>
</artist>
<artist><name>Elisa</name>
<url>https://www.last.fm/music/Elisa</url>
<image size="small">https://lastfm.freetls.fastly.net/i/u/34s/2a96cbd8b46e442fc41c2b86b821562f.png</image>
<image size="medium">https://lastfm.freetls.fastly.net/i/u/64s/2a96cbd8b46e442fc41c2b86b821562f.png</image>
<image size="large">https://lastfm.freetls.fastly.net/i/u/174s/2a96cbd8b46e442fc41c2b86b821562f.png</image>
<image size="extralarge">https://lastfm.freetls.fastly.net/i/u/300x300/2a96cbd8b46e442fc41c2b86b821562f.png</image>
<image size="mega">https://lastfm.freetls.fastly.net/i/u/300x300/2a96cbd8b46e442fc41c2b86b821562f.png</image>
<image size="">https://lastfm.freetls.fastly.net/i/u/300x300/2a96cbd8b46e442fc41c2b86b821562f.png</image>
</artist>
<artist><name>Marco Mengoni</name>
<url>https://www.last.fm/music/Marco+Mengoni</url>
<image size="small">https://lastfm.freetls.fastly.net/i/u/34s/2a96cbd8b46e442fc41c2b86b821562f.png</image>
<image size="medium">https://lastfm.freetls.fastly.net/i/u/64s/2a96cbd8b46e442fc41c2b86b821562f.png</image>
<image size="large">https://lastfm.freetls.fastly.net/i/u/174s/2a96cbd8b46e442fc41c2b86b821562f.png</image>
<image size="extralarge">https://lastfm.freetls.fastly.net/i/u/300x300/2a96cbd8b46e442fc41c2b86b821562f.png</image>
<image size="mega">https://lastfm.freetls.fastly.net/i/u/300x300/2a96cbd8b46e442fc41c2b86b821562f.png</image>
<image size="">https://lastfm.freetls.fastly.net/i/u/300x300/2a96cbd8b46e442fc41c2b86b821562f.png</image>
</artist>
</similar>
<tags><tag><name>soul</name>
<url>https://www.last.fm/tag/soul</url>
</tag>
<tag><name>female vocalists</name>
<url>https://www.last.fm/tag/female+vocalists</url>
</tag>
<tag><name>italian</name>
<url>https://www.last.fm/tag/italian</url>
</tag>
<tag><name>pop</name>
<url>https://www.last.fm/tag/pop</url>
</tag>
<tag><name>alternative</name>
<url>https://www.last.fm/tag/alternative</url>
</tag>
</tags>
<bio><links><link rel="original" href="https://last.fm/music/Alessandra+Amoroso/+wiki"></link>
</links>
<published>19 Jan 2009, 23:36</published>
<summary>Alessandra Amoroso (Galatina, August 12, 1986)&#10;&#10;Italian singer rose to prominence in 2009 with the participation and victory in the eighth edition of the talent show Amici di Maria De Filippi. She released an EP, two albums and eight singles. She was born in Galatina, in the province of Lecce, 12 August 1986 and lives in Lecce up to twenty-two. Since her youth she has participated in numerous competitions locally. In June 2007 she won the second edition of the Apulian peach blossoms. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.last.fm/music/Alessandra+Amoroso&quot;&gt;Read more on Last.fm&lt;/a&gt;</summary>
<content>Alessandra Amoroso (Galatina, August 12, 1986)&#10;&#10;Italian singer rose to prominence in 2009 with the participation and victory in the eighth edition of the talent show Amici di Maria De Filippi. She released an EP, two albums and eight singles. She was born in Galatina, in the province of Lecce, 12 August 1986 and lives in Lecce up to twenty-two. Since her youth she has participated in numerous competitions locally. In June 2007 she won the second edition of the Apulian peach blossoms. At age 17, attended the auditions for Friends of Maria De Filippi, but lost, although the show has passed several specimens. Unable to enter the school in the eighth edition of Friends. The first single of the singer is building, the song reached the top position in FIMI. In January 2009, having obtained the white shirt, the singer admitted to the evening. Is inserted into the blue team and decides to be followed, after a series of disputes, the teacher Luca Jurman. On March 25, 2009 is proclaimed winner of the &quot;Friends&quot;, thus winning the first prize of 200,000 €. On the same evening received the Critics Award, a scholarship worth € 50,000. With this money, Alessandra Amoroso says she will continue to study with Luca Jurman, as well as her intention to purchase goods in for her family and an apartment in Rome. After having presented during the final of the Friends of Maria De Filippi, an evening where the singer is proclaimed winner of the talent show, Amoroso released her first single, &quot;Stupid, March 27, 2009. The single achieved a great success peaking after entry into a minor key, the first position of most downloaded digital singles chart, the FIMI, the song accompanying the release of the singer&apos;s first EP, Stupid, published April 10, 2009, with the &apos;label Sony BMG. The album gets a great success since released went gold, thanks to preorders, later certified double platinum for more than 200,000 copies sold. On 6 June 2009, the love received in Verona Wind Music Awards two multi-platinum for sales of the compilation of the ep stupid and Shaw, the latter withdrew with the other competitors and friends. From 3rd to 8th May 2009 in collaboration with the Admo an awareness campaign on the occasion of a campaign donor multiplies life.The &apos;experience leads her to become an official, December 29, 2009, the association Admo testimonial. The same day the singer is undergoing tests at the typing to be registered as marrow donors Osseo.Durante the summer of 2009, the singer, was with the stupid tour, with tour organized by Battiti Radio Norba Live, Trl On Tour and the production of Amici di Maria de Filippi. Also in the context of the talent show, May 16, 2009, in Turin, take part in Friends - The challenge of talent, a show hosted by Maria De Filippi with some of the players in the talent show the first eight editions of all that is then sent broadcast by Channel 5 June 16, 2009, Amoroso is beaten in the challenge of singing from Karima, a competitor of the sixth edition, the final challenge is won by the ballerina of the second edition Anbeta Toromani. The activity also includes the participation of Amorosa in the summer, August 22, 2009, the night of Taranta in Melpignano but above all, June 21, 2009 benefit concert at the Blink of Abruzzo, created by Laura Pausini, the stage of San Siro in Milan, along with other artists around forty-three in favor of the earthquake victims of Abruzzo. On July 31, 2009, Sony officially announced that September 25 is the date of publication of the singer&apos;s first solo album: Without clouds, also available in a DVD version. The album is preceded by the single Strangers from yesterday, which is broadcast on radio from the end of August. On October 3, Lampedusa is host to the event O &apos;Shah of Claudio Baglioni. On October 8, presented for the first time live disc to the &quot;Limelight&quot; in Milan with entry restricted to winners of various competitions set up by a Radio Kiss Kiss, sponsors - among others - the event, by Fornarina, MTV and fansblog by not only by Sony itself, through the album opendisc content without clouds. Fans were able to attend the screening of the concert in 37 selected cinemas across Italy who broadcast the event live via satellite in high definition.The &apos;event is then repeated, December 20, 2009, in Italy on a third night, getting around the 10 th share. The album debuted at number one in FIMI, which remains in position for four consecutive weeks. The second single from the album is the title track without clouds, which is one of scores of Love 14, a film by Federico Moccia. The video was voted the best clip of the video clip at the Rome Film Festival 2009 December 10, 2009. In November, alongside the singer Gianni Morandi in conducting Thank you all, a variety show, consisting of the first four nights, aired on Raiuno. Along with Morandi, also recorded the duet I believe in love songs in the album of the singer not to be missed. Since November 2009, Amoroso is promoting helped Francis, a charity initiative against a seven year old boy suffering from periventricular leukomalacia. The initiative is to organize a fundraiser through the various fan clubs and a concert singer, December 26, at the Teatro Politeama of Lecce as well as a solidarity marathon organized by Radio Alcamo Centrale. Also in November of 2009, namely 18, is being published a biography of the singer for the unofficial Fanucci Editore, written by Angelo and Gregoris Alessandra Celentano, while in December 2009 showed, along with Deejay All Stars, a Christmas jingle for Radio Deejay entitled This Christmas. Coinciding with the start of the Clouds Live Tour, January 22, 2010 comes into radio rotation the third single from the album, I did you try you. During the third and fourth night of the Sanremo Festival 2010, Amoroso crowd the stage at the Ariston Theatre duettante as: interpretation, the song For all the times that ... Valerio Scanu with the winner of the festival. On April 2, 2010 is the fourth single from the album extract, you Arrivals. On May 8, 2010, the singer participates in the TRL Awards 2010, received two nominations for the category MTV TRL First Lady and My Best Video, also participates in the Wind Music Awards 2010, winning the award for multiplatinum No clouds. During the summer of 2010 the singer was involved with a summer without Clouds Live Tour, a promotional tour of the album Without clouds, which has been certified triple platinum. On July 15, 2010 is the official release of the second solo album from Alessandra Amoroso Sony. The title will be The world in one second, the release is scheduled for September 28, 2010. The album is preceded by the single My story with you, available from 1 September. My story with you is also chosen as one of the soundtracks of Elisa&apos;s daughter 2. Alessandra Amoroso has repeatedly stated preference for black music, soul genre soul, R &amp; B and gospel, which represent the tone blasted the singer, highlighted mainly by Luca Jurman during the talent show to friends and the same teacher associated with the timbre of the singer Lecce to that of Anita Baker. &#10;The new album contains 13 tracks, released just over a week is already first in digital downloads. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.last.fm/music/Alessandra+Amoroso&quot;&gt;Read more on Last.fm&lt;/a&gt;. User-contributed text is available under the Creative Commons By-SA License; additional terms may apply.</content>
</bio>
</artist>
</lfm>
