<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<lfm status="ok"><artist><name>Christian Castro</name>
<mbid>8cc00e45-94c9-40e0-882b-0e76dd5b472b</mbid>
<url>https://www.last.fm/music/+noredirect/Christian+Castro</url>
<image size="small">https://lastfm.freetls.fastly.net/i/u/34s/2a96cbd8b46e442fc41c2b86b821562f.png</image>
<image size="medium">https://lastfm.freetls.fastly.net/i/u/64s/2a96cbd8b46e442fc41c2b86b821562f.png</image>
<image size="large">https://lastfm.freetls.fastly.net/i/u/174s/2a96cbd8b46e442fc41c2b86b821562f.png</image>
<image size="extralarge">https://lastfm.freetls.fastly.net/i/u/300x300/2a96cbd8b46e442fc41c2b86b821562f.png</image>
<image size="mega">https://lastfm.freetls.fastly.net/i/u/300x300/2a96cbd8b46e442fc41c2b86b821562f.png</image>
<image size="">https://lastfm.freetls.fastly.net/i/u/300x300/2a96cbd8b46e442fc41c2b86b821562f.png</image>
<streamable>0</streamable>
<ontour>0</ontour>
<stats><listeners>230</listeners>
<playcount>1799</playcount>
</stats>
<similar></similar>
<tags><tag><name>spanish</name>
<url>https://www.last.fm/tag/spanish</url>
</tag>
<tag><name>latin pop</name>
<url>https://www.last.fm/tag/latin+pop</url>
</tag>
<tag><name>latin</name>
<url>https://www.last.fm/tag/latin</url>
</tag>
<tag><name>pop</name>
<url>https://www.last.fm/tag/pop</url>
</tag>
<tag><name>Romantica</name>
<url>https://www.last.fm/tag/Romantica</url>
</tag>
</tags>
<bio><links><link rel="original" href="https://last.fm/music/+noredirect/Christian+Castro/+wiki"></link>
</links>
<published>30 Dec 2006, 21:44</published>
<summary>Castro began his singing career in 1992 with the release of Agua Nueva. The album received mixed reviews because Castro&apos;s voice was said to be too low-pitched. The album was a big success nonetheless, with the smash hit &quot;No podrás&quot; topping the charts for weeks. After participating in various telenovelas and recording some albums as a teenager, Castro began his &quot;internationalization&quot; in 1993, starting with concerts in Puerto Rico. Castro dedicated a song to that country in his second album &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.last.fm/music/+noredirect/Christian+Castro&quot;&gt;Read more on Last.fm&lt;/a&gt;</summary>
<content>Castro began his singing career in 1992 with the release of Agua Nueva. The album received mixed reviews because Castro&apos;s voice was said to be too low-pitched. The album was a big success nonetheless, with the smash hit &quot;No podrás&quot; topping the charts for weeks. After participating in various telenovelas and recording some albums as a teenager, Castro began his &quot;internationalization&quot; in 1993, starting with concerts in Puerto Rico. Castro dedicated a song to that country in his second album, Un Segundo En El Tiempo, titled &quot;Puerto Rico&quot; as a way of thanking the Puerto Rican public for supporting his career. He also modified his singing voice from the deep voice he employed in Agua Nueva to a softer one that he currently uses. His song, Nunca Voy A Olvidarte (I Will Never Forget You), launched his career. Castro became an international teen idol and sex symbol almost instantly after he began touring, and he began what has been a fructiferous international singing career. Cristian has also done voiceover theme songs for telenovelas such as La Mujer De Madera (The Woman of Wood), Angela, and Morelia. In 1994, Cristian released &quot;El Camino Del Alma&quot;. The album hit, Mañana, meaning Tomorrow, a song composed by Mexican singer, Juan Gabriel which was titled, Mañana, Mañana.   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.last.fm/music/+noredirect/Christian+Castro&quot;&gt;Read more on Last.fm&lt;/a&gt;. User-contributed text is available under the Creative Commons By-SA License; additional terms may apply.</content>
</bio>
</artist>
</lfm>
